Hey everyone, this is an updated video
about installing Sage Attention 2.2 on
both the latest portable and desktop
versions of Comfy UI. So let's get
started. First, we are going to focus on
installing Sage Attention in the
portable version. If you don't know
about this, here it is. Sage Attention
needs Triton to work and Triton needs
certain Python development headers and
libraries to work. The portable version
of Comfy UI comes with an embedded
Python which doesn't have these files.
So we need to get these files and put
them inside that embedded Python. Let's
see how we can do that. So open the
Comfy UI portable folder. In my case,
Comfy UI is located in the downloads
folder. Here is Comfy UI. Let's open it.
Inside we can find a folder called
Python embedded. Let's open it. After
that, let's open a terminal or
PowerShell window right here. Now we are
going to find out what Python version
this comfy UI is using. Type the
following dot/python.exe
space-en capital V then press enter. We
can now see the Python version. The
Python I am using is 3.13.6.
So we need to download the full
installer of the exact same Python
version from the internet and install it
on our computer. The download link for
the Python installer is in the
description. Let's open that link in the
browser. Here we go. In here, we can
find a lot of Python installers. Let's
look for the Python version that we need
right now. So, let's scroll down and
look for Python 3.13.6.
Here we go. Under the name, we can find
the 64-bit Windows installer. Let's
click and download it. Let's save it in
the downloads folder. After finishing
the download, let's open the downloads
folder. Here is the Python installer.
Let's run it. I will select the
customize installation option. Let's
leave the default options as they are
and click on next. Next, I am going to
change the installation location. So,
let's click on browse. I will choose the
downloads folder and create a new folder
there called Python. Then, select that
folder and click okay. Finally, click on
the install button and wait until the
installation is complete. The
installation is complete. Let's close
this window. Next, let's open the
installation folder of Python. In here,
select and copy both folders called
include and libs. Then go back to the
Comfy UI folder and open the Python
embedded folder. Let's paste the folders
we just copied into this location. After
that, let's open a terminal here and
install Triton. So, type the following
command dot /ython.exe
space-en mspace pips space install space
Triton Windows. Then press enter. The
installation of Triton is complete. Now
let's clear the window and check the
torch version the portable comfy UI is
using. So type the following command
dot/python.exe
space-en msp space pip space show space
torch then press enter. As you can see
my portable version uses torch 2.9.0
with q130.
This information is needed for
installing the correct version of sage
attention. So let's open the link for
downloading sage attention. This
download link is also available in the
description. Let's open it in the
browser. Here we go. Let's scroll down.
Under releases, click on the latest
version. Then let's scroll down again.
Here you can see a lot of installation
packages for Sage Attention. In every
file, it is mentioned which package is
made for which torch and CUDA version.
And also all of these packages have
CP39-
AI3 in their names which says that these
packages can be installed in any Python
that is Python 3.9 or above. This means
if your Python is above 3.9 and is part
of the Python 3 series, then you don't
need to worry about the minor version
numbers. But one thing you need to make
sure is that the torch version and the
CUDA version in the files name should be
matching with the Comfy UI torch and
CUDA version. However, in some cases,
you don't need to worry about the CUDA
minor versions as well. For example, if
you are using Torch 2.9.0 with CUDA
12.9, then you don't need to worry about
the CUDA minor version. Just get the
package which says Torch 2.9.0
with CUD to 12.8. In my case, I want a
package which is made for torch 2.9.0
with Q130.
So, this is the package. Let's right
click on this package and copy the link.
Then let's go back to the terminal and
type dot/python.exes
mspace pips space install and let's
paste the link we just copied by using
control and v. Then press enter. The
sage attention package will be
downloaded and installed. After that,
let's close the terminal. Now it's time
to start using Sage Attention. We have
two ways that can be utilized to use
Sage Attention. One is adding a flag to
the Comfy UI launcher and the other
method is using a custom node from KJ
nodes. First, let's take a look at the
flag method. This is the flag we need to
add in the Comfy UI launcher. So, let's
copy this flag and open the main folder
of Comfy UI portable. Here we have the
BAT files for launching Comfy UI. Most
of the time I will be using the run
Nvidia GPU.bat file. So, I am going to
add the flag in this launcher. Let's
open it inside Notepad. in notepad after
the words hyphen windows standalone
build put a space and paste the flag
then save the file now we are ready to
launch comfy UI let's launch comfy UI if
you have added the flag properly the
terminal window will show you that it is
using sage attention after launching we
can start using sage attention now let's
take a look at the other way for using
sage attention for that we need to
install kj nodes use the comfy UI UI
manager to install KJ nodes. Let's take
a look at that. Open the comfy UI
manager and then click on custom nodes
manager. Then click on search and start
searching for comfy UI KJ nodes. Here it
is. In my case, I have already installed
KJ nodes. So guys, if you want to use
the second method, make sure you have
installed KJ nodes. Now let's close the
manager. In this workflow, let's add the
node for using Sage Attention. So double
click and search for patch sage
attention KJ. Here it is. Let's click on
it. We need to add this node in between
the model and the K sampler. In my case,
I have a Laura loader added. So I am
going to connect the model output of the
Laura loader to the model input of patch
sage attention KJ. Then connect the
model output of patch sage attention KJ
to the model input of K sampler. After
that we can start using the options for
sage attention in the patch sage
attention KJ node. We can choose auto or
other options like sage attention qk i n
t 8pvp16quda
or the triton option. I am going to
choose auto. Then let's run the workflow
to check if it is working. When the
generation in process look at the
terminal here it is saying patching
comfy UI attention to use sage
attention. If every step you have done
is correct, the generation will complete
successfully. The generation is
completed. Now let's take a look at the
generated image. Yes, it looks good. Now
it is time to install Sage Attention in
the desktop version of Comfy UI. For my
experiments, I think we don't need to do
the step of copying Python development
headers and libraries to the desktop
version of Comfy UI. So let's see how we
can install Sage Attention in desktop
Comfy UI. So first launch the desktop
Comfy UI. After Comfy UI desktop shows
its interface, click on the toggle
bottom panel option. Then click on
terminal. Let's clear the terminal by
typing clear and pressing enter. First
let's check the Python version by
running the command python space capital
V. The Python that my Comfy UI desktop
is using is 3.12.8.
Now let's check the torch version by
running pipace showace torch. So, my
comfy UI desktop is using Torch 2.8.0
with Q129 support. Therefore, we need
the Sage Attention package that supports
Torch 2.8.0
with Q129.
Now, let's open the link for downloading
Sage Attention. Here we go again. Under
releases, click on the latest version.
Then, scroll down. Here we can find the
Sage Attention package for Torch 2.8.0
with Q128. My Comfy UI desktop uses
Torch 2.8.0 with Q129. But as I said
earlier in this video, we don't need to
worry about the Q to minor version
difference. Also, regarding the Python
version, my Comfy UI desktop is using
above the Python 3.9 minimum. So, like I
said before, we don't need to worry
about Python minor version differences.
We can just download this and install it
in the Comfy UI. So let's right click on
this file and copy the link. Then go
back to the terminal of Comfy UI Desktop
and type pip install. Then paste the
link we just copied by usingtrl +v. Then
press enter. After the installation
finishes, let's install the Triton
package by running the command pip
install Triton Windows and pressing
enter. Here we go. The installation is
finished. Now we are ready to start
using Sage Attention. for using Sage
Attention in Comfy UI desktop. I suggest
using the custom node from KJ nodes. We
learned about it earlier. So, if you
don't have the KJ nodes, use the Comfy
UI manager to install KJ nodes. And
thank you for watching. I hope this
video will help you with installing Sage
Attention in Comfy UI. So, what do you
think about this video? Please let me
know in the comment section. See you
soon with another video. Don't forget to
like, share, and subscribe to this